Ashok Vardhan

Hyderabad, Telangana, India



mva.vardhan@gmail.com



+919949031927



linkedin.com/in/ashok-vardhan-056659b

Summary

30 years in Sales, Channels & customer service. Successful in relationship and team building. Skill in leading the teams to set high sales figures. Expand existing territories and develop new accounts. Generated sustainable revenue EBIT gains with strong P&L and General Management Skills. Blend of Strategy, Channel Management, Product Management, Large Team management, P& L management, Annual Operating Plan, Weekly cadence & Team Reviews

Excellent track record both in central and state Government and consulting on adoption of technology, Enterprise sales, CXO relationship, key account management including global accounts, product management with P& L responsibility, large complex projects in enterprise and Government along with services sales business and working with OEMs, channel, Systems Integration Partners and volume channel partners.

Alliances with key industry partners and top MSIs & SIs. Execution and Country experience. Donned a variety of roles in the technology domain –E Governance, Enterprise Cloud, Digitalization, Digital transformation, Workspace management, Mobility, enterprise resource planning software, enterprise networking and security, enterprise professional services, Virtual reality Centers, High-end Storage Solutions, Facility Management Services, Print Solutions, Card Solutions, Surveillance & Security Solutions, Banking (Core banking Infra, Datacenter build).

Worked in Manufacturing, Telecom, Infrastructure, e-governance domain with various departments in State Govt like Land Records, Panchayati Raj, Tribal Welfare, PDS, Education, State Crime, Smart City & Safe City, Irrigation, Strong experience of working in Projects on Rural Health, Skill development, E Courts, Digitization Projects in Panchayati Raj, Land Records, eSeva in AP & Telangana, eGov in Karnataka, High End Storage and High Computing projects in Dept of Space and Defence classified projects.. Nature of engagement is Technology consulting, scoping, project management, SI & Alliance Management, Regulatory framework and documentation, RFQ & RFP generation and participation.

Work Experience

Esri India Technologies Limited (5 Years 2 Months) Sr.Zonal Sales Manager (South) – Jun 2016– Aug 2021

In my existing role as the Sr.Zonal Sales Head, I have been able to build a strong team which is focused on helping government organizations in solving greatest challenges in the areas like management of water and other natural resources, forestry, land management, mapping, disaster management in the territories of Telangana, Andhra Pradesh, Karnataka, Tamil Nadu, Kerala & Pondy. The role involves Strong Sales strategy and Accelerating Business Growth in the field of GIS (Geographic Information System) software. GIS is relevant for every area of governance and enterprises. Successful in getting new logos viz to the organization and addressing the customers social and business challenges using GIS

HP Inc (Formerly Hewlett Packard PSG Division) 4 Years 9 months)

National Manager (Commercial Channel Mobility) - Sep 2015 - Mar 2016 (7 months)

Strategize and build Mobility Partnership Club to stamp HP leadership in this space and build a strong ecosystem of partners who'll specialize in various segments and be consultants to the customers. Responsible for Mobility Business through Commercial Channel Partners and align them with various ISV's to drive Mobility in

different segments / Vertical. Also Work very closely with Sales team to scale the skill level of partners to address this growing segment.

Zonal Manager (Commercial Channel) – Oct 2012 - Sep 2015 (3 years)

- Channel Management Managing Channel Partners of around 30 Managed Final Tier and 250 Non -Managed Final Tier Partners.
- Supervised a sales force of 10 sales associates
- Geo-Expansion Up Country Biz in SMB and Mid-Market Biz. SMB & Mid Market Biz Growth YoY & QoQ across Andhra Pradesh (Now Telangana & Andhra States) through Channel Partners Built relationships with Partners and the community to establish long-term business growth.

Regional Business Manager (Enterprise) -Jul 2011 - Sep 2012 (1 year 3 months)

- Responsible for Biz Growth from Enterprise Accounts in the territory of Andhra Pradesh, West Bengal, Bihar, Jharkhand and the Classical East Territory.
- Supervised a sales force of 6 sales associates. Exceeded regional annual sales target by 230%.
- Supported the sales team in writing proposals and closing contracts.
- Attended sales training camp and brought best practices leadership back to the company.
- Built relationships with customers and the community to establish long-term business growth.

CMS Info System Pvt Limited (7 Years 1 Month)

Dy.General Manager - Apr 2010 - Jul 2011 (1 year 4 months)

- Responsibility includes monitoring P &L, Operations, Finance & accounts and Administration for a total strength of the region of 800+.
- Supervised a sales force of 10 sales associates to drive the System Integration Biz in the territories of Andhra Pradesh & East.
- Driving the Services Biz (New), Contract renewals of existing customers services, enhance the professional services biz
- Focused segment viz., BFSI, PSUs, State Govt.,
- Built relationships with customers and the community to establish long-term business growth.

Regional Sales Manager – Jul 2004 - Apr 2010 (5 years 9 months)

- Revenue generation from Sales Team which includes IMG (Infrastructure Management Group) & SMG (Solutions Management Group).
- Service Revenue from Maintenance & FMS.
- Responsibility includes monitoring operations and Administration for a total strength of the region of 800+.
- Driving revenue generation from Sales Team of IMG Group
- Exceeded regional annual sales target by 140 %.
- Supported the sales team in writing proposals and closing contracts.
- Built relationships with customers and the community to establish long-term business growth.

<u>Area Manager - Accel ICIM Systems & Services Limited- Mar 2003 - Jul 2004 (1 year 5 months)</u>

- As a Area Manager, the responsibility is to Head the Sales and drive the rejuvenated a lethargic team. Significantly impacted the company's long term business direction and ensured its survival.
- Achieve budgeted Sales Quota Quarter on Quarter across all services offerings for the Andhra Pradesh Region and maintain an average estimated gross margin as per the organization's expectations.
- Maintained a very high customer satisfaction index and ensure that the entire team achieves their Sales Quota individually.

Area Manager - DCM Data Systems - Jun 2000 - Feb 2003 (2 years 9 months)

Responsibility includes the increase foot print and revenue in the segments of State and Central Govt departments along with BFSI. Successful in growing the revenue YoY and with a very strong presence in Banking with addressing the core banking requirements with almost all PSU banks.

<u>Area Sales Manager - CMS Computers Limited - May 1997 - Jun 2000 (3 years 2 months)</u>

Key responsibility is to increase the coverage and develop new customer base in Defence and Govt Segment. Achieve agreed target and focus on solutions selling in the defined territory

Account Manager - Zenith Computers Ltd. - Jul 1994 - May 1997 (2 years 11 months)

Promote Zenith brand of PCs & Servers in Corporate Segment. Achieve agreed target in the defined territory. Coverage in the area of Corporate & Banking Segment.

<u>Marketing In charge - Cache Peripherals Pvt. Ltd.- Jan 1992 - Jun 1994 (2 years 6 months)</u>

Cache Peripherals was a Printers distribution company, dealing with brands like TVSE & HP. They have signed up with Unicorp for the PC business with brands of Unicorp and Compaq. The responsibility includes to lead the PC division sales team to promote Unicorp, HP and TVSE brands

Education

HN COLLEGE OF COMMERCE – Shivaji University

MBA, MARKETING & FINANCE (Dual Major Specialization) 1989 - 1991 **St.Marys Boys' High School**

Schooling, SSC 1979 - 1983

Honors & Awards

- > Promising Debutant of the Year (2017) Esri India
- ➤ Elite PBM (Partner Business Manager) HP Inc APJ Region (Dec-2014)
- Best Zone HP-PSG (Nov-2012) Hewlett Packard
- ➤ ROOKIE OF THE YEAR IN 2011 HP-PSG HEWLETT PACKARD
- Best Channel Performance SGI (2006-07)
- Best Region CMS Info Systems (2006-07)
- ➤ Best Group Leader CMS Info Systems (2005-06)